I know the hot topic will be, you know,
or some of the hot topic other than the
the draft will be Dexter. Uh just a
quick quick update on that for you guys.
Um we've had good conversations with his
representatives
um throughout the last five or six days.
Coach Dawn, myself, we've all been in
communication um you know, trying to
find some resolution. I'll echo what
coach said last week. You know, we'd
like for Dexter to be here and at some
point we'll we'll come to a resolution
here. um whatever that may be. Uh we'll
see. But conversations have been really
good. Uh they've been productive and
again, we'll we'll see what happens here
down the road. But um I'm not going to
say any more about it after that. But
that's that's the update. That's really
all there is. So with that being said,
I'll open up for any questions.
>> Look at the first round of the draft
then as a deadline with Dex to get
something done because if you were going
to move, if you're going to grant his
request, you would want something for
this year's team. So does that act as an
unofficial deadline? Yeah, I'm not gonna
I'm not going to get into it on if
there's deadline or not. Um you know,
he's under contract for two more years.
So, um we're not going to put any
deadlines on anything. Again, right now,
productive conversations and you know,
we'll see where it goes.
>> Joe, are you entertaining offers? Are
you are you listening to offers when
teams call about him or is that you're
trying to figure out something to keep
him here?
>> Yeah, I'm always going to pick up the
phone. So, if if team calls um you know,
maybe not to the effect that coach said
last year that every or last week that
everybody is tradable, but no, that is
my job as a general manager. If teams
call, um, you take into account, it's
it's case by case basis and what the
compensation may be. And that's that's
my job to, you know, to take into
consideration what that looks like, what
the compensation looks like, who the
player is, how that affects the roster,
and then, you know, try to make the best
decision off of that.
>> How has that impact how has this trade
request impacted the way you're
approaching the draft position?
>> Um, it really hasn't. It really hasn't.
Um, you know, we're going to continue to
go through our process. Um the scouts
left yesterday so they had been here for
roughly 14 days and you know so now
we're putting the final touches on the
board but it really hasn't affected how
we're uh approaching the draft.
>> Joe, there's always that expression best
available player and that we'll look for
that as as a staff. Are you looking for
that or are you looking for ways that
you need things? Are you addressing
needs? How do you kind of balance that?
Ideally they line up you know when the
best player best available players also
a position in need but you know I would
say last year if you look at what we did
with Abdul you know we had Kavon and we
had Burns here and we still took Abdul
so um we were you know really strong at
outside backer when we added uh Abdul to
the roster so similar we're going
through we're going to stack the board
and you know the best player available
is is the direction we'll go. the sheer
volume of players that enter the draft.
How do you view draft picks in terms of
just the collecting of talent and
bringing to your roster
>> in terms of how many picks we have or
just having more picks overall or
>> just having picks overall? Like you
don't treat one different than the
other?
>> Um yeah, I guess you know my first year
we had you get more swings. Again, more
swings, you know, the better chances of
of hitting, you know, so um and it also
allows you to to build depth, you know,
at different parts of the draft. you'd
like them for all to become starters,
but there are certain parts of the draft
where you're looking for either special
teams or you know depth pieces if
somebody gets injured. So, um you know,
I look at all those as you know there
they're they're it's an avenue for us to
upgrade the roster um at different
levels throughout the draft. And you
know, ideally when you when you go into
it, you you know, you want to find
somebody that's going to be able to help
you in the short term and the long term
ideally. How unique just philosophically
uh as an evaluator when do you move off
of your initial evaluation
seeing that a player comes out here and
played maybe a year or two. When does
that move off the original evaluation
you had as a prospect?
>> You're saying if they come to the league
and they're better or worse than what we
>> change your mind.
>> Was it a guy we drafted or a guy in the
league or just in general? Well, yeah. I
mean just it's predicated on how the
player plays and um you know we talk
about that sometimes in our meetings if
like somebody brought up a guy the other
day it's like oh this guy reminds me of
player X well depends like if we pulled
this room half of the room may not allow
lot of player X. So in my mind that's a
negative but this half of the room it's
a positive. So you know you got to be
careful sometimes when you compare
players to different players. So um you
know what you really want to worry about
is the players that you pick not the
ones that you didn't pick. You really
want to hit on the ones that you pick
and that's really what's most important.
How unique is this draft at the top?
There seems to be a lot of non premium
positions compared to the past and how
much does that change or maybe alter
slightly alter the approach?
>> Yes, this this draft exactly I mean
you're you're dead on with with what you
said there in terms of you know maybe
it's not the you know the surplus
position or the higher paying positions
when you get into free agency or outside
the be building may be the best players
in this draft. So, um, again, goes back
to where we are roster-wise and in a
being in a position to take the best
player available regardless of position.
So, um, yeah, in a in a in a perfect
world, when you look at the fifth pick
and then you slot in whatever position
you want, like what that player is going
to make at the fifth pick, where does
that slot him in APY right off the bat?
Okay, well, it's fifth pick and it's a,
you know, corner. Where's that? Fifth
pick and a receiver. Okay, he's 40th.
fifth pick and a running back, maybe
it's 11, fifth pick and a tackle, you
know, I mean, you start going through
it. Um, you would like to have, you
know, again, those positions outside the
building that you're going to pay a lot
of money, you know, to get that surplus
value, but, you know, that just may not
be the case this year, which is fine.
We're going to evaluate, uh, every
position, every player, and um, you
know, obviously do what's best for us.
>> Running back, that would put it around
10th, I think, some somewhere in that
range.
>> Yeah. So that's that's
>> how much would that affect your thought
process on taking a player
>> at that position?
>> We're gonna take the best player
available, Jordan, and we're not going
to rule we're not going to rule any of
those out. But but yeah, your point in
the the original question, that's you
know, that's part of our thought process
when we go through the evaluation as
you're building the team. Um you know,
you do go through those scenarios. Joe,
have you got a sense that, you know,
from from the owners meetings and
talking to people just getting there'll
be more of this later on that more teams
will want to go down or up? You know, do
you get a sense that it's going to be,
as you said, this is not a normal draft.
There's one quarterback and so are more
teams going to want to go down and is
any are there enough teams to want to go
up? It takes two.
>> Yeah. And it depends. We we always think
and I you know, everybody sees the the
lead the board their board looks just
like ours. You assume the way you're
looking at it. So, yeah. Yeah, I mean at
some point there's a Mendoza line where
maybe there's a drop off and you know
the player at eight may be the same type
of player you can get at 18. So maybe
there's really not a big difference in
those. So yeah, at some point, you know,
some teams may want to, you know, move
back because of that, but at the same
time, they might want to get into that
top eight or 10 or 11 or whoever that is
for for that particular team may want to
get inside of that to get, you know, a
significantly better player potentially.
So, um, you know, we we we've gotten a
couple calls of, you know, teams
sniffing around about potentially coming
up and, you know, again, we'll just have
to wait and see, you know, who's there
when we pick. Um, you know, I don't
really foresee us moving back before,
um, next Thursday night.
>> And do you think, um, um, you know, you
don't have a third round pick? There's a
good reason why. Um, but but do you does
that does the quest for more picks, you
know, you always want more picks. Is is
the quest for more picks really strong
in you this year if it's possible to do
that?
>> Yeah, Paul, I would always I would
always like more picks, but it'll be
situational. We're not going to walk
away from a a impact player or a good
player that that we're convicted on that
we like, you know, to pick up, you know,
an extra pick or a couple extra picks.
So, um, case by case basis, if there's,
you know, if you move back three or four
spots and there's five five guys you
like, you get an extra pick, absolutely.
If it's if it's a guy you're convicted
on and you know maybe there's a big drop
off from let's say it's a a corner and
there's a big drop off maybe two rounds
to the next corner um you maybe don't
roll the dice in those situations. You
just take the player you know so you
don't miss out. So um certainly would
like more picks but um you know don't
want to walk away from good players
either.
>> Joe, you talked about in the past the
process by which you set up possible
trade percentages in first round, second
round. What about the the pressure
involved when you're on that phone? I
mean, what what confidence do you have
in your process that allows you to do
that and to know you only have a a
limited time and you've got to kind of
pull that trigger? You've moved up,
you've moved back. I mean, I think it's
five trades on draft day uh since you
took over as general manager. What What
is that like? What is that process like?
>> Yeah, h have a really good team in
there. um you know between Brandon,
Brandon Brown, Tim McDonald, Dennis
Hickey, you know they have the trade
calculators and Dawn will be in there
this year with the the trade calculator
assistant at that. So you know those
guys are always and and Dawn will be
thinking of trades. If teams call, you
know, I'll say it out loud. They'll go
through the different charts. Does it
make sense? Should we ask for more? So
you know we'll we'll have conversations
while we're on the clock going through
some of those different scenarios. Um
and then we'll be able to make a
decision. It's it's easier in the first
round a lot of times because you know
you're you know that the rounds are you
know that you get a longer time to make
the pick and then you know you're having
these strategy meetings leading up to
that. Um you know second third round it
happens a little bit more rapid. So um
again just having a really good um you
know group of people around me that can
help um you know take the information
and and get it in front of me as quickly
as possible so we can make the best
decision. Is there pressure involved for
you to kind of pull that trigger in that
situation just personally to to make
>> to make the deal? I mean, you have the
final call, right, in that situation?
And, you know, you've done it, like I
said, I think it's five or six times on
draft draft night. I mean, it's
>> Yeah. And for for example, last year
with Jackson, that was something we
actually had a deal in place with
another team and until they actually
accept it when you're on the clock, um,
that ended up falling through. So, we
kind of had trade parameters in place.
we knew what the value was and you know
we pulled the trigger on that to to move
up and you know to get Jackson but a lot
of the thought process and the planning
and strategy going into that had been
been done beforehand. So you know it's
almost like you play the game before the
game you know especially in the first
and second you know going into that
early pick in the second round. You've
got all day you know for the first round
pick we've we've had months to prepare
for. So you know we'll be ready.
>> Directions do you think based on what
you guys do with the fifth pick? How
many different directions do you have
for that second round pick of of where
you guys could go?
>> We could get back up into one if you
know we did this this probably a week
ago. I looked at it. We could get back
into one, but not very far. You know, we
don't have a third. So, you know, if we
wanted to go back in one, it might be a
little bit more difficult, but it's, you
know, it's not out of the question. We
could do it, but we'd have to give up
some picks. But um could certainly go
back, you know, typically top of the
second, you know, top of the fourth
where we are on Saturday. Um you know,
you'll get people they they sit around
all night and they look at the board and
there's somebody they they have to have
and um you could typically move back
from the early parts of those rounds and
you know, day two and and day four, you
got a pretty good chance of doing that.
>> Positionally, based on what you do with
number five, how many different sort of
directions could you go with that
filling another need there? Yeah, and we
we've set it up and for those of you
who've been here like so we can go play
we could go play game on Thursday. Are
we as good as we want to be? Can we
still add to Certainly, you know, we had
um I know it was reported, you know, we
had DJ Reer in here yesterday. Like
we've had some people come in on visits.
Um there's still players that are on the
street that were free agents this year
that are available. So um again, just
try not to back yourself in a corner
where it's a need. Um it's where
mistakes can be made. you know, maybe
the guy's really a third round player
and you you take him in the second
because that's the last one left and you
know, that sets the expectation of the
level the player is supposed to be
playing at. So, to the best of our
ability, just try not to back ourselves
into a corner where you have to draft or
need
>> based on based on your based on your
running back situation, would you
consider a 20year-old running back who
combines speed, power, and vision at
number five?
>> We like our running back room now. Uh,
you know, Scat had a really good rookie
of year. Tyrone Tracy's been a thousand
yard allpurpose guy the last two years.
Devin's back, you know, Turbo, Eric Gray
coming off the energies injury. So, um,
you know, we'll see what happens on
draft night, but like like the room the
way it's constructed right now.
>> Trying to steal my running back thunder
here.
>> I know you love the running back.
>> So, I'm gonna So, I'll ask uh to use a
premium pick on a running back. that be
saying that it was a mistake two years
ago to devalue the running back position
or what's changed since then that it
would be worth using a valuable asset on
it?
>> Yeah, I would say the we're in a
different place. Uh we have a rookie on
a a quarterback deal. Uh rookie on a
quarterback a quarterback on a rookie
deal. Um you know, at that time our
offensive line was different. You know,
we didn't have Germaine Aluminor. Uh we
didn't have John Renan. Um we didn't
have Brian Burns. We didn't have Malik
Neighbors. Um,
so the roster was different and there's
there's a time and a place um, you know,
to, you know, in terms of the roster
construction. Um, you know, I like where
we are right now from the young nuculus
and that was a little part of the
thought process is, hey, we need to we
need to build this thing. Um, you know,
and it started up front and last year we
were fifth in the league in rushing. We
were fifth in the league in rushing a
year ago. So, um, I think mission
accomplished. we upgraded the offensive
line and improved the run game. Um, and
I thought we had to start by doing that
up front and we did that. So, um, again,
we're we're going to look for the best
player regardless of position and, um,
you know, I'm excited about where the
roster is right now based on what we did
in free agency. Um, you know, the the
the prospects of what we can get here a
week from now, uh, coach Harbaugh, the
new staff, some of the new leadership in
the building. Um, you know, I like the
trajectory we're on. When you have a
player like uh Jeremiah Love, do you
look at him as a straight running back
though or do you look it as an offensive
weapon? How do you kind of look at a
player like that when they have the
skill set that he obviously
>> an offensive weapon? Yeah, he's an
offensive weapon. I mean, he's not just
a running back like he can play on third
down, you can split him out, he can
catch the ball. So, um certainly an
offensive weapon. You talked about best
player available, but just given how
much Harbaugh talked about stopping the
run as a priority, how tempting is it to
look at the defensive guys and say,
"Hey, a player like maybe Styles or DS
or someone like that could be a
potential at five just to say, hey, we
want to continue to upgrade the defense
a little bit more."
>> Yeah. And that wouldn't be out of the
question. I mean, those those are really
good football players and you know,
those are the conversations we're having
right now like, "Hey, we like all these
guys, but you got to pick one." And you
know, a couple of them are going to be
there. So, we're working on stacking
that right now. But um you speak of
Sunny Styles and Caleb DS like talk
about talented defense. We've watched a
lot of Ohio State defensive film the
last uh couple of months. A lot of good
football players from from top to bottom
on that defense and you know those are
two of the you know the key players on
that defense uh that we looked at. So
you know certainly guys that we've
talked a lot about and think very highly
of.
>> Joe, you spent um four years with one
head coach and kind of trying to figure
out where your philosophy is and what
his is and trying to get him the
players. This is a new head coach,
obviously a big profile head coach. So,
how has that gone? And could could your
six players or seven players that you
draft be more of a reflection on what
his vision is for what the roster is?
Because, you know, you want to get him
the players that he can do well with.
>> Yeah. The the best way for this to work
regardless of the organization of all 32
is, you know, there be a collaborative
effort and be on the same page. So,
the early returns on that, it's been
great. Like, we've had a lot of fun.
He's passionate, you know, coach
Harbaugh's passionate about the draft.
I'm passionate about the draft. My
staff's passionate about it. So, just
the ongoing football conversation
sitting in a film room with him. Um
whether it's walking through the board
or watching the film. Um you know, it's
it's been it's been a lot of fun. It's
been a lot of fun. We spent a lot of
time together uh working through, you
know, not just first rounders, second
rounders. I mean, he's he's passionate
about it. Like he knows about fourth and
fifth rounders. uh he's sending me text
messages asking about, you know, maybe
undrafted free agents, you know, where
he saw an article or a an agent might
have text him. So, um you know, he's
really passionate about the the draft
and, you know, it's been it's been a lot
of fun being in these meetings and
watching film with him and it's going to
be a collaborative effort. Like, we're
going to be on the same page. We're
working towards that. You know, by next
Thursday, uh when we get to the first
round, you know, we'll all be on the
same page.
>> Your vision for what a player is and his
is similar because sometimes it's not.
You know, sometimes it's like, I want
this and you don't. that's not your
priority.
>> Yeah, it's pretty simple. We joke around
like just good football players, you
know, it's that's not over complicated
and you know, we joke about that all the
time. Just just take good football
players and you know, that's uh
philosophically we're aligned on that.
>> You need to do more at the guard
position. Vanroen is still on the
street, right?
>> Yeah, correct.
>> Do you need to do more to
>> Yeah. Yeah. We we'll see. Um again,
we've we still got the draft. There's
people on the street. Greg Van Roen, as
you mentioned, still on the street. So,
um, one of the cool things about having
a new coach is we get to be on the
field, you know, next week. So, we'll
get to see some of those, uh, some of
the new guys move around, which will be
exciting. But, uh, not just, you know,
offensive line. We're always going to be
looking to to upgrade the O line, Dline,
every position really. Um, like I said,
we brought some guys in earlier this
week and we'll continue to do so. But
again, you know, Daniel started multiple
games for, you know, the Ravens over the
last couple years. you know, Evan
started games, Stenny started games.
We've got placeholders in there. Um,
guys that have done it will compete.
Audu, you know, get an opportunity
inside at guard, but, you know, we'll
also continue to look, you know, outside
the building as well as, you know, the
draft coming up.
>> When you look at the uh this draft in
general, where do you see the strengths
in the middle rounds positionally, you
know, day two into maybe probably early
day three?
>> Yeah, I would say the outside backers. I
mean, it's a it's there's some depth
there at the outside backers. I would
say wide receivers a a position of depth
and then, you know, the the corner
position, you know, I think in those
those mid rounds, those guys typically
get pushed up. So, um I think you'll see
some guys go from those positions there.
>> Joe, you've talked about in the past the
idea of when you you're setting your
board and then maybe there's a bump for
for need or positional value, that kind
of thing. Have you kept your philosophy
and how you put together the board with
your team uh with the new coaching staff
and the new head coach and John's input?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we we're going through that
stuff now and he's asking questions
because it's first time he's done
something, you know, one way for 18
years. So, we we've had constant
communication throughout the process
when I was, you know, okay, here's how
our meetings go. Here's because there's
also a like I need to get to the to
where I need to get to. So, here's my
process to get me where I need to get to
to draft day. um what do you need to get
where you need to get to where you're
comfortable and you know we kind of
merge the calendars to you know get us
to where we need to be next Thursday but
uh philosophically it there's really not
much difference from you know what they
did in in Baltimore and and and what how
we you know our process to get to draft
day